<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>daily on Xangelo.ca</title>
    <link>https://xangelo.ca/tags/daily/</link>
    <description>Recent content in daily on Xangelo.ca</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2011 - 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 06:01:42 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xangelo.ca/tags/daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monday, June 5th, 2023</title>
      <link>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/june/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 09:56:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/june/5/</guid>
      <description>Caching is a bad idea until you have some concrete numbers as to why you&amp;rsquo;re caching a thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday, June 4th, 2023</title>
      <link>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/june/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 09:47:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/june/4/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noodling around in the fediverse for a long time now, entranced by some of the ideas Diaspora had when it first launched.. and mostly just continually disappointed by the various communities that tend to spring up around it. Hoping this foray into the activity-pub based world (kbin, lemmy, pleroma) will be different. But already the main lemmy instance is proving to be a bad one specifically because of the devs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday, June 3rd, 2023</title>
      <link>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/june/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 06:08:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/june/3/</guid>
      <description>In a strange twist, it appears that I may be more of a morning person than I though. The last few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to bed by 9:30 (kids&amp;hellip;) and then waking up at 4am and starting my day. It&amp;rsquo;s been a strange experience. By about 7am I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get a bunch of work done and had time to walk the dog before the 30 degree weather kicks in and melts her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday, June 2nd, 2023</title>
      <link>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/june/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 10:36:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/june/2/</guid>
      <description>There was something magical about uploading the wordpress zip file to your shared host and going through install.php</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday, May 30, 2023</title>
      <link>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/may/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 11:12:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/may/30/</guid>
      <description>I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m ALMOST there on the process for deployments. I think right now I need to adjust the build process so that after I write a post in the outliner, it gets pushed up to github automatically (the raw data) which builds and deploys it to github pages. That way the &amp;ldquo;built&amp;rdquo; info isn&amp;rsquo;t in github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday, May 26, 2023</title>
      <link>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/may/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 13:33:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/may/26/</guid>
      <description>Everyone wanting their own streaming service is just re-inventing cable and the whole reason that services like Netflix &amp;ldquo;distrupted&amp;rdquo;. Gabe Newell said it best &amp;ldquo;[Piracy] is a service issue&amp;rdquo;. And the service here sucks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday, May 25, 2023</title>
      <link>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/may/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 21:20:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/may/25/</guid>
      <description>I have a sneaking suspicion that Azure DevOps is way better than GitHub but no one is willing to admit it.
For whatever reason this year has been really bad on my allergies. I&amp;rsquo;m trying a variety of over-the-counter medications but will likely have to resort to something a bit stronger before the summer is out.
I just realized that all the &amp;ldquo;Daily Updates&amp;rdquo; are already one day out of sync due to the fact that I don&amp;rsquo;t know what day it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday, May 24, 2023</title>
      <link>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/may/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 23:11:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xangelo.ca/daily/2023/may/24/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m attempting to adopt Dave Winer&amp;rsquo;s posting setup of daily updates. I realize there&amp;rsquo;s so much that I want to just say over the course of the day. Some of it might morph into full blown posts.. some of it will just disappear. I originally thought I would try and transition some into &amp;ldquo;tweets&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;toots&amp;rdquo; or whatever mastodon calls them.. but for now they&amp;rsquo;ll just live here.
I moved to hugo about a year ago, mostly to gain the easy github pages integration&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m only now beginning to discover some of the neat details that made it so popular.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
